# Shweta Kumari

### AZURE CLOUD ENGINEER

### **PROFILE INFO**

I am a qualified and professional Azure Cloud Engineer with Two years of experience in Infrastructure as a Service (laaS) with Strong creative and analytical skills. who possess the Knowledge and skills of Azure Compute Resources, Active Directory, and Cloud based Development, Azure Migration and several such services, which can be utilized for mutual growth and development of organization and myself.

# CONTACT

B	<b>PHONE</b> +91 7978771315
$\bowtie$	<b>EMAIL</b> Jhashwetakumari11@gmail.com
0	ADDRESS  Darbhanga, bihar

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **AZURE CLOUD ENGINEER**

Feb 2024 - Nov 2024

Sirius Global. LTD., Noida

- 2.3 Years of professional experience in Microsoft azure as an azure administrator.
- Worked on Microsoft Azure Cloud to provide laaS support to client. Experience in managing azure active directory identities.
- Hands-on experience with virtual machines, virtual network, Azure storage, Azure active directory, Backup and Monitoring.
- Azure Admin with hands-on experience in building, deploying and maintaining scalable infrastructure.
- Create and configure a virtual network with private & public IP addresses of Azure resource.
- Configure local and global virtual network peering.
- Upgrade or downgrade server size, Disk size as per application requirement.
- Configuring virtual machines backup, File and Folder backup.
- Create and configure Azure Blob Storage, File Storage, Queue storage and Table storage and managed disk.
- Creating File share for copying server data to azure.

CMS IT Service PVT LTD., Noida

Aug 2022 - Jan 2024

- Installed software
- Fm engineer
- Domain & profile configuration
- Administration knowledge
- Assets management
- Itil
- Bitts tool Knowledge/ Zoho Tool

## **SKILLS**

Directory (Azure AD) users, create custom Azure Role Based Access Control (RBAC)roles, and assign these roles to Azure AD users.

Protecting disk resources from being accidentally deleted and implement and test resource locks.

Configure local and global virtual network peering

Creating and implement Azure Load Balancer.

Creating and implement Azure Application Gateway.

create and configure Azure Storage accounts. Manage authentication and authorization for Azure Storage.

Create and configure an Azure Files shares Scale compute and storage for Azure virtual machine.

Configure Azure virtual machine scale sets by using virtual machine extensions. Review default monitoring settings of Azure virtual machine.

### **PROJECTS**

# MICROSOFT AZURE BACKUP ACCORDING TO ZONE REDUNDANCY

### Responsibilities:

- Configuring the Recovery service vault with standard configuration, like security configuration, backup configuration and system configuration.
- Creating the snapshot for the disaster recovery. Creating the jump boxes for the safe running or virtual machines.

# NETWORK CONNECTIVITY BETWEEN CLOUD NETWORKS, MICROSOFT AZURE

#### Responsibilities:

- Creating resource groups and virtual networks.
- Creating the jump boxes for the safe running or virtual machines.
- · Managing the azure load balancers.
- Configure Azure virtual machine scale sets by using virtual machine extensions. Internet
- •
- · connectivity for global peering

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

MICROSOFT AZURE FUNDAMENTALS AZ-900 CERTIFIED (I107-7268)

MICROSOFT AZURE ADMINISTRATOR AZ-104 CERTIFIED (1132-3627)

**AZURE ACTIVE DIRECTORY: BASICS** 

# **EDUCATION**

> 2014 - 2018 B.P.U.T UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Engineering Majors in CSE

### **PERSONAL INFO**

> Date of Birth: 11 Dec 1994

Languages: English, Hindi

Hobbies: Technology enthusiast,Traveler, Exploring new places,Watching TV series.